Guide to the Evelyn Byrd Robinson Papers, 1785-1940
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Evelyn Byrd Robinson papers 1785-1940
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Robinson, Evelyn Byrd.
2.0 linear feet Extent: 415 Items
Daughter of Dr. Clifford Cabell of Buckingham County, Va. Papers and correspondence of Evelyn Byrd (Cabell) Robinson, who married William Russell Robinson, resident of Nelson County, Va. There is also some material related to her two sons, Clifford Cabell Robinson and Wirt Robinson, who taught at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point for many years. Includes some genealogical material, writings by Evelyn Robinson, early legal papers, and an obituary of Wirt Robinson. The correspondence is chiefly of a personal nature, and the bulk of it dates from after the Civil War.
RL.01114
Language: Material inEnglish
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Evelyn Byrd Robinson Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 1974.
Biographical Note
Evelyn Byrd (Cabell) Robinson was the daughter of Dr. Clifford Cabell of Buckingham County, Va., wife of William Russell Robinson of Nelson County, Va., and mother of Clifford Cabell Robinson and Wirt Robinson.
Collection Overview
Collection includes papers and correspondence of Evelyn Byrd (Cabell) Robinson, who married William Russell Robinson, resident of Nelson County, Va. There is also some material related to her two sons, Clifford Cabell Robinson and Wirt Robinson, who taught at the U.S. Military Academy at West Point for many years. Includes some genealogical material, writings by Evelyn Robinson, early legal papers, and an obituary of Wirt Robinson. The correspondence is chiefly of a personal nature, and the bulk of it dates from after the Civil War.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Cable family; Robinson, William Russell; Robinson, Wirt, b. 1864; Robinson, Clifford Cabell; Robinson family; United States Military Academy; Women -- Virginia -- Correspondence; Domestic relations -- Virginia; Nelson County (Va.)--History
Contents of Collection
- Evelyn Byrd Robinson Papers, 1785-1940, (5 boxes)
  - Correspondence, 1820's-1940 and undated, (4 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Legal Papers, 1815-1910 (Box 2)
  - Financial Papers, 1814-1874
  - Addresses and Writings, undated, (2 Folders)
  - Addresses and Writings, 1886-1887 and undated
  - Addresses amd Writings, 1877-1878 and undated
  - Geneaology, undated
  - Printed Materials, various dates and undated
  - Various Pictures (Box 3)
  - Pictures: People--Douglas, Henry Kyd, undated (Box 4)
  - Pictures: Geography--N.Y., West Point, U.S. Military Academy, undated
  - Pictures: People--Robinson, Wirt, undated
  - Pictures: Geography--Virginia, "Colleton" undated
  - Autograph Book, undated (Box 5)
  - Small Ledger, 1841
  - Small Ledger, 1864-1866
  - Notebook, 1838-1853
  - Scrapbook, various dates and undated
  - Ledger, 1886